<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Example Index on</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/</link><description>Recent content in Example Index on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vulnerability</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/vulnerability/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ve found a bug. We&amp;rsquo;ll provide an example bug. Forget any previous vulnerability risk framework you&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years, including color coding, zero-to-ten scales, or high/medium/low. We&amp;rsquo;re going to think about the bug critically and communicate the nuances that distinguish this bug from other bugs.
Example: We&amp;rsquo;ve found an internet exposed Jenkins server (build001) with the scripting console accessible.
Probably familiar to you. A very common vulnerability many of us have run into.</description></item><item><title>Vulnerability Impact</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/vulnerability-impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/vulnerability-impact/</guid><description>Impact can be frustrating to work with because a variety of undesirable outcomes may or may not happen. Unless we&amp;rsquo;re forced to translate everything into dollar values, we can work with whatever quantities we&amp;rsquo;re concerned about.
Example Scenarios # Let&amp;rsquo;s assume the following scenario:
Scenario: An SQL injection is discovered in our product. These scenarios assume that an SQL injection has already been exploited.
Users Compromised: Sensitive data for more than 100 customers will be impacted.</description></item><item><title>Mitigation</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/mitigation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/mitigation/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s assume we found a vulnerability on a host named build001.
👉 This example vulnerability was discussed here. The vuln # The vuln is bad. It&amp;rsquo;s an RCE exposed to the internet, allowing for remote compromise right now. It&amp;rsquo;s a feature of our CI/CD system, and is effectively a remotely accessible shell running as root.
There are complicating factors:
Several partners companies remotely access build001 The script console that offers a shell to the host is used regularly.</description></item><item><title>Breach Impact</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/breach-impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/breach-impact/</guid><description>We may be asked what the impact would be if we suffered a breach. The following questions are useful to ask when thinking through a model.
Did we discover this breach? Are we talking about response costs? Are we talking about costs from an undiscovered breach? IP theft / Corporate espionage / competitive threats Do we strictly mean financial costs? Or measurements in engineering hours, days offline, etc Are we counting costs imposed to others (imposed risk)?</description></item><item><title>New Product Review</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/new-product-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/new-product-review/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a new product. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss some hypothetical risk scenarios, and then discuss some estimations for them.
Scenario: We launch a feature that lets customers upload profile pictures. Discussion # This change allows &amp;ldquo;User Generated Content&amp;rdquo; or UGC onto a platorm. UGC can have multi-dimensional impacts.
Allowing new UGC into a product workflow creates many operational risks that will result during the lifetime of the product, as well as risks that would be infrequent but potentially devastating.</description></item><item><title>Registers</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/registers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/registers/</guid><description>Many risks can be compared quantitatively so long as they share a measurement.
Let&amp;rsquo;s compare a bunch of vulnerabilities we are treating as risks. We assume we have VULN-0 to VULN-9. If we have a common group of forecasts for all of them, we can sort and manage them as you&amp;rsquo;d expect.
Vulnerability (1 year) Exploited? (Exploited) Dislosable? Headline? VULN-0 2.00% 5.00% 5.00% VULN-1 3.</description></item><item><title>Team Direction</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/team-direction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/examples/team-direction/</guid><description>We want our teams to work in a unified direction. This section describes codifying that direction as a risk. Codifying a risk is similar to selecting a KPI or setting an objective.
These directional risks should be broad. There shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be many of them, as we&amp;rsquo;re using it to provide a meaningful north star. Using incident classification (SEV, P0, etc) helps clarify what incident means, as well as thresholds of other undesirable things like costs or losses.</description></item></channel></rss>