<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/introduction/</guid><description>Simple Risk Measurement teaches security engineers about quantitative risk.
Examples: Find your a-ha! moment by looking through creative approaches to problems.
Guidance: Avoid gotchas and pitfalls that make risk measurement treacherous.
Management: Find the optimum place for risk measurement with groups of people in a workplace.
Reading material is suggested throughout this documentation for those who want to dive deeper into the concepts, or see Reading Material.
See the blog for examples and discussion with current events.</description></item><item><title>Industry</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/industry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/industry/</guid><description>Cyber security is compared to other industries for its lack of rigorous and quantitative analysis of risk. Simple Risk Measurement focuses on quantitative risk measurement to assist with this imbalance. While cyber security may lacks the forms of rigor found in other industries, this documentation also seeks to mitigate known weaknesses found in those approaches.
What makes other industries quantitative about how they handle risk? How are we so different? Well, here are some examples, and we&amp;rsquo;ll start with one you see all the time.</description></item><item><title>Measurement</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/measurement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/measurement/</guid><description>The definition of measurement is probably more inclusive of methods than you would expect.
Philosophers, standards bodies, and scientists all hold that measurement is approximation. They all assume that uncertainty exists in measurement. They all endeavor to reduce it.
We often use an objective instrument to measure something, but this does not eliminate uncertainty. For instance, we may use a ruler to measure the size of a table. When an objective instrument does not exist&amp;hellip; we rely on increasingly unreliable methods.</description></item><item><title>New forecasters guide 🎉</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/for-noobs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/for-noobs/</guid><description>Do you want to forecast stuff? You&amp;rsquo;re in the right place!
I don&amp;rsquo;t know how! # First, don&amp;rsquo;t worry! This is actually very simple.
Overall, the process is Forecast, talk, update forecast.
First, get a forecast in. This is easy:
All you&amp;rsquo;re being asked is to type some numbers. You won&amp;rsquo;t have to show or discuss your work. You&amp;rsquo;re not committing to anything long term. Forecasts are default anonymous. You will finalize it later, so just get something down.</description></item><item><title>Risk</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/risk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/risk/</guid><description>This section includes conceptual discussion to support your intuition around risk. A grasp of risk concepts will improve your ability to comprehend risk problems as well as articulate them to others.
Language # This documentation mostly cares about quantitative risk, which has a strict definition (See Math below). However, the term risk has lots of useful interpretations. Miscommunication with others is common without clarifying what you are measuring.
Sven Ove Hansson describes risk with many definitions:</description></item><item><title>Scenarios</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/scenarios/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/scenarios/</guid><description>We use scenarios to specifically define future events and impacts that we'd like to measure. This must happen before we start measurement, either through the collection of historic data or through expert elicitation.
In our discussion about risk we discussed the likelihood and impact of a future event, as r = p * i
A point of failure in measurement is ambiguity about a risk problem being solved. A group of very smart people can spin in circles discussing a risk if they don't pin a specific outcome down first.</description></item><item><title>Decisions</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/decisions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:11:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/intro/decisions/</guid><description>Decisions are subjective. This documentation is about making quantitative risk measurements. These measurements will not make decision making an objective process. We are still bounded by rationality. Risk based measurements will only be a subset of all information available for a decision.
This documentation can only offer methods to improve the quality of risk based measurements for those decisions, and offer commentary on decision processes themselves.
Data driven decisions # Often discussed is the data driven decision.</description></item></channel></rss>