<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Help on</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/enterprise/</link><description>Recent content in Help on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Organizing Risks</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/enterprise/organizing-risks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/enterprise/organizing-risks/</guid><description>An enterprise has a lot of varying risks. We want to organize them and work collaboratively to understand them.
What we don&amp;rsquo;t want is a single person or team to assess and understand all the risks across an organization. Some federation of risk assessments need to occur, and we can do this by following the third axiom of probability when decompose a risk to share as a study.
A single engineer working in isolation should be capable of modeling a risk and developing measurements for it.</description></item><item><title>Decision Standards</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/enterprise/decision-standards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/enterprise/decision-standards/</guid><description>Carl Sagan once said &amp;quot;Extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence&amp;quot;. For us, extraordinary decisions follow the same principle.
Leadership can require that a risk measurement meet certain requirements that defend it against negligence, cognitive error, corruption, imaginative failures, or gaps of evidence.
Here are some example thoughts on standardizing the level of expense expected for a measurement.
👉 For a real-world example, see NASA-STD-7009 Level Zero: An individual, &amp;ldquo;water cooler&amp;rdquo; estimate.</description></item><item><title>Performance</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/enterprise/kpi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/simple-risk/docs/enterprise/kpi/</guid><description>Having an available method to quantify risks may not translate well for measuring individual or organizational performance. Trouble awaits for those who assign incentives (bonuses, promotions, etc) for directionally favorable changes in risk measurements, especially ones that rely on expert elicitation.
However, Key Results (OKR) and KPIs are still valuable leadership tools that assume values (in this case, a risk measurement) may correlate with some notion of success. While these approaches has leadership value, there are rough edges with metrics based management to consider which especially painful with risk metrics.</description></item></channel></rss>