<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Expert Elicitation</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/expert-elicitation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:11:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/expert-elicitation/</guid><description>We have to make decisions about risks&amp;hellip; often with imperfect information. Data may not be available, may not be timely to gather, or measurement options may not yet exist. We may be left to use data with only a loose relationship with the target problem, or nothing at all.
The response to these situations may be to trust experts who have developed the most intuition around these risks and elicit numerical values from them.</description></item><item><title>Scoring and Calibration</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/calibration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/calibration/</guid><description>Scoring and calibration mitigates the largest weaknesses of qualitative risk methods and empowers us to correct ourselves over time. Investing in ongoing correction is an opportunity to shine over other industries that have difficulty doing so, for whatever reasons.
Remarkably, most intelligence organizations do not proactively track their forecasting accuracy and, therefore, do not know how accurate their forecasts are or what types of biases intelligence analysts (or organizations) might exhibit.</description></item><item><title>Percentiles</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/percentiles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 10:34:55 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/percentiles/</guid><description>A percentile estimate is a probability and value pulled from a distribution. Some examples:
The 90% percentile of customer losses is $1M.
This communicates a 90% chance that future customer losses will be $1M or less.
It also communicates a 10% chance that losses will exceed $1 million.
The upside: A percentile estimate is very simple to gather and communicate.
The downside: It won&amp;rsquo;t communicate how the risk behaves.</description></item><item><title>Intervals</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/intervals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:12:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/intervals/</guid><description>An interval estimate can be described as a range of values, plus the probability that an outcome will fall within them. More formally, these can be called probability intervals, or credible intervals.
Intervals can also be thought of as the values between two percentile values on a distribution.
Here are the exact same statements with increasing formality. Each communicates an interval:
Here&amp;rsquo;s a statement that could be an interval with one more bit of information:</description></item><item><title>Strategy</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/strategy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:12:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/strategy/</guid><description>Estimation is a skill that benefits from approximation strategies. These mental models will help support common problems in risk modeling, elicitation, and forecasting. They&amp;rsquo;re also useful as elicitation techniques when trying to draw out numeric estimates from an expert.
Divide and Choose # Divide and choose is a mental heuristic to determine if odds are fair or not. It is similar to the children's &amp;quot;fairness&amp;quot; concept:
One child slices a piece of cake Another child chooses the slice they'd like.</description></item><item><title>Distributions</title><link>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/distributions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 13:12:05 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://magoo.github.io/risk-measurement/docs/estimation/distributions/</guid><description>Nearly all of the estimation methods in this documentation so far are actually components that could be obtained from a probability distribution if one were available. You&amp;rsquo;re likely familiar with the well known normal distribution, shown below:
Other topics discussed so far are simple components of a probability distribution.
A percentile is the sum of all probabilities up to a value on a distribution. An interval communicates two percentiles from a distribution.</description></item></channel></rss>